# Marco Talaat Basaly

# PHP - WORDPRESS

2/8/2000

marcotalaat355@yahoo.com

**L** 01202937338

https://marco-talaat.netlify.app/

in marco-talaat-b349911a0

# **Profile Summary**

WordPress Developer with +3 years of functional experience in SEO, designing and managing business websites using WordPress creation tools. Skilled in front-end and back-end development and implementing themes and plugins. Successfully creates attractive and user-friendly websites to meet client expectations in agile environments. Built WordPress functions, creating custom post types and developing widgets to conform with Wordpress coding standards. Over +4 years of programming, javascript and ajax experience.

# Experience

**PHP - WORDPRESS** iLamp Agency

9/2021 - Present

#### • <u>LaCosta Real E</u>state

Real estate multilanguage website, adding custom features for theme using custom ajax to make search criteria when you choose a developer in the developer menu, it will filter the projects menu according to the developer chosen I make it custom using ajax.

#### Powerful

For powerful international company contains a custom post type I made it using PHP code, not plugins this reduced number of plugins lead to enhanced performence of the website.

#### Katameros

Used custom post type like Powerful company.

#### jGT

Digital Marketing website responsive for all devices . added attractive designs suitable for content.

#### • Expertise Globe

A form created from scratch using PHP and MySQL contains: admin page has full control and displays registered users with their details, you can accept or ignore registered users and it will send a custom email for users if accepted or ignored automatically, it also contains filter users upon anything. if you want to send a special certificate, for example, you can upload all certificates at one time and it will send for each one automatically based on ID or Phone number

## PHP - WORDPRESS UpWork

2020 - 2021

- Created and updated re-usable code libraries to streamline WordPress development cycle
- Redesign layouts.

## Front end developer Freelancer.com

2019 - 2020

- Built a form connected with google sheets.
- Built responsive real estate website.
- Built and styled new mobile-friendly websites, transitioning legacy presentations to simultaneous easyto-use versions

## Skills

- HTML5
  - IVILO
- CSS3
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- BootStartp
- PHP
- AJAX
- WordPress
- GitHup
- OOP
- Algorithms

Data Structures

## **Education**

Veterinary medicine

Sohag University

#### **Graduated**